

# **My Contact**

anashesham000@gmail.com

**(**) +(20) 01140106552

5th settlement , Cairo Egypt

www.github.com/anas12312

in <u>www.linkedin.com/in/anas-hesham-87871a19a/</u>

#### **Technical Skills**

- Backend Development
- JavaScript (ES6, React.js, Node.js, Electron, React Native)
- Java (Spring, Swing)
- C# (ASP.Net)
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- Typescript
- HTML/CSS
- · Problem Solving
- Git
- C++
- AVR
- Embedded C
- MatLab

#### **Soft Skills**

- Observation
- Problem Solving
- · Decision making
- Communication
- Multi-tasking

## **Education Background**

- Electronics, Communication and Computer Engineering
   Faculty of Engineering Helwan university
   09/2019 - Present
   Accumulative Grade (Very Good)
- Secondary School
   El Redwan Private School
   Completed in 2019

# **Anas Hesham**

# Software Engineering Student

#### **About Me**

Ambitious and approachable Software Engineer equipped with High knowledge about core Computer science principles, looking forward to improve my skills and gain as much experience and knowledge in Software engineering as possible.

Throughout my (6 years) Software Engineering learning journey, In order to improve significantly I have focused on writing as much code as possible while trying to achieve scalable and well-documented solutions.

## **Professional Experience**

#### Freelance Software Engineer

2021 - Present

- Worked on a food delivery application as a Backend Engineer team lead in a team composed of 6 members
- Developed a fully-customized point of sale and management system for a warehouse
- Been a part of team developing an E-learning platform for online courses and lectures
- Developed custom software solution for many clients using different technology stacks

#### **Research Developer**

2020 - 2022

WRL - Wireless Research Lab

Achievements/Tasks:

- Worked in a Learning Management System under the supervision of Dr. Mahmoud El Mesallawy the dean of the faculty.
- Used C# and ASP.Net as a backend framework in real projects.
- Supporting various team members to carry out research, and analyze their work.
- Developed a basic understanding of the different methodologies of project management.
   Contact Dr. Mahmoud El Mesallawy

#### **Embedded Systems Instructor**

Aug.2022 - Oct.2022

Faculty of Engineering Helwan University

Was one of the instructors in the 3-month summer training provided by the faculty to the undergraduate embedded engineering students, and was responsible for teaching: (C Basics - Data Structures - Pointers - Embedded C - AVR Interfacing - Git/GitHub)

Contact Dr. Mohamed El Dakroury

# **Personal Projects**

- Resource Management Platform that holds team resources like links and files (React.js - Node.js - MongoDB - WebSocket - Tailwind -Authentication - Authorization - Push Notification)
- RC Car with hand gesture control (AVR UART Bluetooth Modules Flex Sensors)
- Electronics Circuit Helper Application that helps electronics engineers find their components and all related information to it (React-Native -Node.js - PostgreSQL - WebScrapping)
- POS (Point Of Sale) and a Store Management System that can fit any type of store regardless of its purpose with a permission-based user service (Desktop GUI - Java Swing - MySQL -Authentication/Authorization)
- User Interface for Spectrometers (LabView Arduino VISA)